NAA Records 5775
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Legislation, Committee on, 1953 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  "Report of Committee on Legislation, May 2, 1953"
- Membership Committee, 1976-1978 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  Correspondence regarding expenses, 1978; Letters concerning the partisan mark of Raymond Roberts, 1978; Letter concerning and actual drafts of rejection letters to Dr. William Weinberg and Dr. Bruce R. Boals; Correspondence regarding the application forms (the forms themselves), 1977-78; Letters regarding, and actual application lists and biographies; Degeral letters to applicants, 1978; Correspondence from G. Jay Taylor providing additional information for his application, 1976; Acceptance lists and letters to accepted applicants, 1977; Thank you letter from Eva Robins to Ms. Bette Cruilt concerning gift, 1978; Letters concerning, and actual rejection letters to applicants, 1978.
- Membership Committee, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  List of new members and letters staffing the committee, 1980.
- Membership Committee, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  Correspondence concerning the application of David U. Brown, questioning his acceptability to parties, 1969; Letter staffing committee, 1969.
- Membership Committee, 1970-1980 (Box 36, Folder 18)
  Correspondence and reports concerning the question of whether or not to admit to membership fact finders, 1970-71; Bylaws amendment, proposed Section 6 to Article VI, has to do with applicant selection and notification procedure, 1974; Letter regarding Membership Certificates for new members, 1976; Report of Special Committee, 1980.
- Membership Committee, 1950-1956 (Box 36, Folder 19)
  "Statement of Policy Relative to Membership Applications", 1956; Annual Committee Report, 1950; Annual Committee Report, 1951; Annual Committee Report, 1955; Letter concerning pending applications for membership, 1953; Letter regarding four issues raised before the committee: 1. Experience or lack of, 2. Character and ethical conduct of applicant, 3. Partisan affiliation or interest, 4. Government employees having power to designate arbitrators; Letter summarizing the responses of regions on membership dues; Report of Special Committee to Examine Qualifications for Membership.
- Membership Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 36, Folder 20)
  Letter regarding the change of address of Daniel Kornblum, 1964; Letter concerning the request for an application form of Joseph V. McKenna, includes a brief biographical sketch, 1964; Correspondence regarding the request of John P. McGury for reconsideration, 1964; Biographical resumes of applicants, 1963; Letters regarding J. Willard Carpenter's request for an application form, 1963; Sympathy letter in regards to the death of Michael I. Komaroff, 1963; Letter concerning the return to health and work of O. Jay Anyon, 1963; Correspondence regarding the whereabouts of Academy member Wilmer A. Watrous, 1963; Letters concerning the application and deferral of Wayne T. Geissinger, 1963; Correspondence concerning the cues payments of Clyde Fimery, 1963; Letter announcing the Committee's meeting, 1963; Correspondence regarding the election to membership of John F. Arraway, Charles T. Douls, Milton T. Edelman, J. Barton Dillingham, Daniel Gutman, Robert O. Howellett, Dallas Jones, Bora Laskin, Bernard D. Meltzer, Thomas T. Roberts,..., 1963; Letter regarding the signing of the Certificate of Membership, 1963; Thank you letters from newly admitted members, 1963; Letter announcing new members of the Nominating Committee (1963); Sympathy letter in regards to the death of Dan A. West (1963); Letters informing new members of their acceptance (1963); Correspondence arranging that new members get: a copy of Labor Arbitration and Industrial Change, address plates made, copies of the insurance material card information, and certificates of membership made (1963); Letter regarding the change of address of Benjamin H. Wolf ( 1963); Letter concerning W. P. Halloran's request for an application form (1963); Letter regarding the Annual Volume and its being late (1963); Letter concerning Betram F. Wilcox's changing of address (1963); Sympathy letter in regards to the death of John O. Kellor (1963); Letter regarding the dues payment (or lack thereof0 of Bernon H. Jensen (1963); Letter concerning the applicants' biographies (1963); Excerpted minutes from the October 26, 1963 meeting of the Board of Governors concerning the report of the committee, and also copy of report(1963); Biographical resumes and comment form (1963); Correspondence concerning biographical resumes and their distribution to the members, resumes included (1963); Misc. correspondence including: dues payment, requests for applications, condolence letters, notices of address change (1963); Rejection and deferral letters (1963); Letters concerning a suggestion to establish a separate region for the general area of Kentucky, Southern Indiana and Southern Ohio (1963); Committee`s report excerpted from the minutes of the Board meeting (1963); Letter from president (Sylvester Gerret) welcoming new members (1963); Correspondence regarding dues: failure to pay, release from, statement inadvertently mailed (1963); Correspondence concerning new members, ensuring they get insurance material card information, have Academy Certificates of Membership inscribed, have address plates made (1963); Acceptance letters to new members, 1963; Letter regarding the mailing of the applicant's files, 1963; "National Academy of Arbitrators Statement of Policy Relative to Membership"; Biographical summaries of applicants, 1963; Letter regarding tremendous membership response to mailing on applicants, 1963;(Up to here, all 1963 material, none to 1962.) Material concerning dues; Letter concerning the new members' certificates (1962); Acceptance letters to new applicants (1962); Letter regarding the sending of insurance information to new members (1962); correspondence regarding certain members' failure to pay dues (1962); Letters concerning new members, their notification, the printing of their membership certificates, and the embossing of their address plates (1962); Correspondence regarding Byron R. Abernethy's request for membership certificate(1962); Letter to correct the spelling of George Shultz's name, a new member (1962); Biographical resumes of applicants (1962); Letter concerning the reapplication of Milton T. Edelman (1962); Correspondence concerning the mailing to members of insurance information (1962); Letter from Lawrence E. Seibel stating he would attend the Board of Governor meeting(1962); Correspondence concerning refection letter to Eugene Hughes and membership directories (1962); Letter staffing committee (1962); Application form requests (1962).
- Membership Committee, 1953 (Box 36, Folder 21)
  Biographical information re applicants
- Membership Committee, 1960-1968 (Box 36, Folder 22)
  Copies of biographical resumes with comment sheets in blue folders (1968); Letter concerning status of applicants (i.e. some being processed, others asked to withdraw) (1962); Hand written notes(probably from committee meeting) containing comments and apparently votes on new applicants (no date, judging by names probably 1961-62); Correspondence regarding the reconsideration of Myron L. Joseph's application (1962); Letter concerning the re-application of Edward L. Merrigan (1961); Letters regarding transfer of new application files (1961); Letter from Eugene Russell, must have accompanied his application (1961); Correspondence regarding the re-application, after one year deferral, of John F. Caraway (1961); Letters regarding Edward Merrigan`s application for membership (1961); Letter from the Secretary (Houghton) requesting new applicant files and inquiring about Eugene H. Hughes' application for membership (1961); Letter inquiring as to whether or not any royalties are due the academy from BHA (1961); Letter from Wayne T. Geissinger regarding his "Arbitrator's Qualification Report" which contains false information and which he does not know the origin of - wishes it to not be considered with his application(1961); Letters regarding corrected application forms (blank); Biographical resumes of applicants (1960-61).
- Membership Committee, 1952-1959 (Box 36, Folder 23)
  "Report of the Special committee on Membership Status" and Minority Memorandum (1959); "Annual Report of the Membership Committee" (1955); "Statement of Policy Relative to Membership Applications" (1956); Biographical resumes of applicants(1952)
- Membership Committee, 1957-1958 (Box 36, Folder 24)
  Biographical resumes of applicants; Letter regarding membership applications and a proposed change (1958); Biographical resumes of applicants with decision written next to ezch name n.d.; Letters regarding the sending out of mailings (1958);Correspondence concerning, and actual biographical resumes of applicants (1957-1958).
- Membership Committee, 1948-1980 (Box 36, Folder 25)
  Correspondence regarding the disappearance of the minutes of the May meeting of the Membership Committee (1979); Letter regarding proposed corrections to committee report (1980); Recommendations for the language of amendments to the bylaws proposed at the first meeting (1948).
- Membership Committee, 1951 (Box 36, Folder 26)
  Biographical resumes of applicants along with some responses
- Membership Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 36, Folder 27)
  Copies of the Committee's report, some drafts, and related correspondence
- Membership Committee, 1965 (Box 36, Folder 28)
  regarding the question of the qualification of the staff and board members of mediation agencies to be members of the Academy (1965).
- Membership Committee, 1983-1986 (Box 36, Folder 29)
  Application of, and correspondence from Robert Kubie (1986); Deferral letter to Lloyd L. Byars (1985); Application of, and correspondence concerning James M. O'Reilly(1985); Letters requesting update of applicants' status as arbitrators (1984); Correspondence regarding request of Robert W. Smedley for reconsideration for membership (1984); Letters concerning a Supreme Court case dealing with "discovery of membership application files" (1984); Letters assigning some Membership Committee members to new committees (1984); Letter staffing Membership Committee (1984); Correspondence regarding the transfer of membership committee files (1984); Misc. handwritten notes - appear to be notes taken of a meeting (1984); Letter concerning and actual final draft of new application form (1983); Letter relating recent activities of the Committee: number of applicants rejected, accepted, deferral, number of requests for applications, and questions about five year experience requirement (1984); Correspondence concerning staffing the committee (1983); Application of, and correspondence concerning Josef Rohlik (1984); Misc. handwritten notes (1983-1984); Letter concerning the suggestion that the Academy consider conferring membership on Board-approved applicants at the Fall educational conference as well as at the annual meeting (1984); Misc. handwritten notes (1984); Biographical resumes of applicants (1984); Misc. handwritten notes (n.d.); Letter requesting application forms (1984); Application of James E. Westbrook (1984).
- Membership Committee, 1957-1977 (Box 36, Folder 30)
  Biographical resumes of applicants, comment form attached (blank) (1967); "Report of the Membership Committee to the Board of Governors" (1957); Letter with list of new members (1977); Biographical resumes of applicants (1977); Biographical resumes of applicants (1964); Letter to applicant redirecting his request for an application to the secretary or the committee chairman (1973); Letter regarding proposed Section VI of the bylaws, and a copy of the proposal section (1974); Letter relating the responses of agencies who use fact finders to the Special Committee on Standards for Memberships questionnaire (1970); Report of the Special Committee on Standards for Membership; Report in relation to the question of admitting to membership individuals with past and current experience as fact finders in the public sector (1971).
- Membership Committee, 1967-1969 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  Biographical resumes of applicants with blank comment forms (1969); Form used to notify members what will be printed under their name in the Membership Directory, and to solicit any required changes (Blank). This form also notifies members of the decision not to print titles (other than clerical ones) (1969?); List of new members and their addresses (1967).
- Membership Committee, 1949-1977 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  Correspondence regarding the reapplication for membership of Henry L. Sisk, includes and article he wrote (1974); Cover letter for the application materials sent to Edward B. Krinsky (1976); Letter arranging for the inscription of several "replacement" Certificates of Membership (1974); Correspondence regarding the transfer of copies of the Membership Directory (1975); Letters requesting application materials and the cover letters sent by the Academy to the applicants with such materials (1974); "Erratum 1976-1977 Directory" (small sheet of printed paper, lists five names and addresses, probably an insert for the Membership Directory); Sheet of columnar paper, some handwritten figures on it (appears to be accounting, but unclear for what) (1965?); Application for membership of Angus Munro (1951); letters of thanks for acceptance into the Academy (1951); letter informing the applicants of their acceptance (1951); letter from member stating no objection to any of the applicants (1951); Handwritten notes, appear to be from a committee meeting, contains results of the committee's vote on each applicant (1957?); Letters from I. Robert Feinburg to Carl Schedler and William E. Simkin, regarding the following: calling of a committee meeting, whereabouts of some applications, statistics on a number of applications; and report as chairman of the committee at the next annual meeting (1951); Letter from applicant Irving Bernstein which accompanied an article of his, also inquires as to any developments on his application for membership (1950); Letter concerning the transfer of an application (1950); Letter concerning when to have the committee meeting before the Board of Governors' meeting (1950); Letter from I. Robert Feinburg, committee chairman, stating that he will attend the Board of Governors' meeting, and inquiring about the arbitration conference at the University of Pennsylvania (1950); Letter regarding the Board of Governors meeting, and the distribution of biographical resumes to the membership (1950); Letter from academy member Byron Abernethy requesting an application be sent to Livingston Smith (1950); Correspondence transferring the application of Michael I. Komaroff (1950); Letter concerning the circulation of pending applications to the membership, and the time of next committee meeting (1950); Correspondence regarding the transfer of applications and committee meeting minutes (1950); Letter regarding the transfer of 4 new applications (1950); Letter requesting application materials (1950); Letter concerning a new list of academy members (1950); Correspondence regarding/accompanying Irving Bernstein's application for membership (1950); Letter from the Academy to Spencer D. Pollard confirming that the committee has received his application (1950); Letter transferring two applications (1950); Letter from member requesting blank application forms (1950); Letter notifying Pearce Davis of his acceptance into the academy (1949); Correspondence regarding the transfer of committee meeting minutes and applications (1950); Correspondence inquiring as to which applicants were accepted, and what the Board of Governors' action was on the application of Albert J. Hoban (1950); Letter requesting information to be printed in the newsletter concerning each region's activities (1950); Letter requesting feedback from the membership on the applicants, handwritten on the sheet are the applicant's names with "yes" or "no" written next to them (1950); Correspondence concerning a date for a committee meeting (1950); Letter advising applicant Joseph G. Stashower of his acceptance into membership (1950); Letter from an Academy member requesting applications be sent to David W. Hill and Robert L. Stutz (1950); Letter regarding the issue of applicants for membership who are on the staff of the New York State Board of Mediation (1950); Reply to a letter requesting an application, request transferred to chairman of the committee (1950); Letter expressing thanks for the transfer of a letter (1950); A request for the list of applicants admitted to membership on January 18, 1950 (1950); Letter concerning Hubert Wyckoff, and sending him an application (1950); Handwritten notes, appear to minutes of a committee meeting (n.d.); Letter staffing the committee (1950); Letter regarding procedure in processing applications (1950); "Membership Committee Report" (1950); minutes of a committee meeting (1950); Correspondence regarding the notification of rejected applicants, and what should be done with their files (1950); Letter listing the present applicants with brief comments about them (1950); Condensed qualifications of applicants sent out to membership for comments (1949).
- Membership Committee, 1971-1975 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  "Report of Special Committee on Standards for Membership", concerns agencies who use fact-finders (1971); List of applicants, some handwritten notes by the names (1975); Correspondence concerning newly admitted members, includes: letters notifying applicants of their admission, correspondence arranging for the inscription of Certificates of Membership, correspondence arranging that they be sent the current Volume of Proceedings, and a letter arranging the mailing of insurance material (n.d.); Mailing labels, most blank (n.d.); Applicant lists with handwritten comments (1973-74); Cover letter for Certificate of Membership sent to the president for signing (1974); Correspondence to applicant, includes: letters of acceptance, letters of rejection, correspondence arranging for the inscription of Certificates of Membership, letter arranging for the mailing to new members of insurance material, and correspondence arranging that the new members be sent the current Volume of Proceedings (1973); Cover letter to Membership Certificates sent to the president for signing (1974); List of applicants with handwritten comments, also attached are drafts of letters to: rejected applicants, and Academy regions, referring certain application decisions to them (1972); Handwritten list of newly admitted members (1973); Letter listing the applicants admitted to membership, includes some handwritten comments (1972); Letters notifying applicants of their admittance (1973); Cover letter transferring the transcript of some session (1973); Letters listing newly admitted members, includes handwritten comments (1972-1973).
- Membership Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  Letter informing Frances Bairstow of her acceptance into the academy (1972); List of names and addresses of new members, also included: a letter arranging for the inscription of their membership certificates, a letter arranging that they be sent the current Volume of Proceedings, and a letter arranging they be sent insurance material (1972); Biographical resumes of applicants, have either the word "O.K." or "rej." handwritten by each name (1972); Copy of dues check from Canadian member (name illegible) (1972); Cover letter to payment of dues, also, cover letter to academy Dues Statement reply (1972); Letters informing applicants of their acceptance (1972); Empty reply envelopes from members, probably held dues payments (1972); Constitution and Bylaws; Cover letter to signed Certificates of Membership (1972); Handwritten list of some academy member names with checks by most of them (n.d.); Letter arranging that the current Volume of Proceedings be sent to new members (1971); List of names and addresses of new members (1971); Letters informing applicants of their acceptance (1972); Letter with list of the names and addresses of new members, also: proposed draft letters to several deferred applicants and proposed draft letters to regions notifying them that they should examine an applicants case (1972); Letters sent to deferred applicants (1972); Dues Statements (1971); Letter to Edwin R. Teple, chairman on the Ohio Region, requesting that he examine the case of applicant Samuel L. Chalfie (1972); Letters notifying applicants of their acceptance (1971); Letters making arrangements for new members, includes: sending of insurance material, imprinting and signing of Certificates of Membership, and sending of current Volume of Proceedings (1972); Correspondence thanking members for their dues payments, copies of certificate attached (1971); Letter arranging the inscription of Certificates of Membership for the new members (1971); Letter from new member thanking the academy for admitting him, and noting his payment of dues; Letter from member concerning applicant David Kaplan. Questions amount of time the applicant "spends as an attorney representing parties" (1971); Biographical resumes of applicants with hand-written comments by each name, for instance, "O.K." or "No Deferred" (1971); Biographical resumes of applicants (1971); Cover letter to dues check from new member, also thanking for admittance (1971); Copy of Alfred J. Goodman's dues statement (1971); Letter notifying applicant of his acceptance (1971); Letters making arrangements for new members: inscription of Certificates of Membership, sending of current Volume of Proceedings, and sending of insurance material (1970); Letters sent to deferred applicants (1971); Copy of Alfred C. Dybeck's dues statement (1970)
- Membership Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, reports, and other material concerning
- Membership Committee, 1957-1967 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  Correspondence, reports, and other material concerning the insurance program, the material dates back to the inception of the plan
- Membership Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 38, Folder 7)